Lucas Lange

Salomonstraße 18B, 04103 Leipzig, Germany

□ (+49) 173-9664700 | ■ lucas.lange@arcor.de | 🏕 lucaslange.de | 🖸 luckyos-code | 🛅 lucaslange

Summary_

I am a computer scientist passionate about artificial intelligence, machine learning, and privacy. At Leipzig University, I am currently pursuing a Ph.D. in computer science. An environment of diverse knowledge exchange is essential when researching a subject. I like to adopt an agile prototyping approach to test hypotheses and make educated decisions quickly.

Experience_

Leipzig University Leipzig, Germany

RESEARCH ASSISTANT (WISSENSCHAFTLICHER MITARBEITER)

Mar. 2022 - present

- Ph.D. research in "Privacy-Preserving Data Analysis" with a focus on machine learning.
- · Conducting/supervising computer science courses at Leipzig University, especially in the field of databases (tutorials, labs, seminars, lectures).

InfAI - Institute for Applied Informatics

Leipzig, Germany

RESEARCH ASSISTANT (WHK)

- Oct. 2019 Feb. 2020
- · Working individually on the ShapBiRd project, an effort to create a linked data infrastructure and workflow for the institute's bibliography. —

 github.com/AKSW/shapbird
- Tools: Docker / Compose, RDF, SHACL, Webhooks, and Python

eccenca GmbH Leipzig, Germany

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jun. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Visual Editor Based on SHACL Shapes (Bachelor Thesis).
- · Specification and implementation of a visual editor for linked data knowledge graphs furthermore, adjustable to specific domains by utilizing SHACL shape descriptions.
- Tools: React.js, SHACL, and SPARQL

InfAI - Institute for Applied Informatics

Leipzig, Germany Jul. 2017 - Apr. 2018

Apr. 2019 - Jan. 2022

STUDENT ASSISTANT (SHK)

- Tutored an agile software engineering student project at Leipzig University.
- Tools: JavaScript, Java, SPARQL, RDF, and Agile Project Management

Education

Leipzig University Leipzig, Germany

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Mar. 2022 - present

• Topic: Privacy-Preserving Data Analysis (Focus on Machine Learning).

Leipzig University Leipzig, Germany M.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

• Thesis: Privacy-Preserving Detection of COVID-19 in X-Ray Images.

Université Grenoble Alpes (UGA) Grenoble, France

ERASMUS+—M.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

· Courses in Machine Learning and Robotics.

Leipzig University Leipzig, Germany

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Oct. 2015 - Mar. 2019

· Thesis: Visual Editor Based on SHACL Shapes.

Projects_____

DP-X-COVIDScaDS.Al Dresden/Leipzig

☑ GITHUB.COM/LUCKYOS-CODE/DP-X-COVID

- Privacy-Preserving Detection of COVID-19 in X-Ray Images (Master Thesis).
- The goal of this work was to implement a private image classifier for COVID-19 X-ray images.

 The model was trained by applying privacy-preserving machine learning procedures to produce a private model and thus prevent attacks from causing data leakage.
- Tools: Deep Learning (CNNs), Differential Privacy (DP-SGD, PATE), Tensorflow/Keras, Python, Jupyter, and Google Colab

X-COVID

☑ GITHUB.COM/LUCKYOS-CODE/X-COVID

- Detection of COVID-19 in X-ray images.
- Binary (COVID-19 vs. normal): 97.8%, Multiclass (COVID-19 vs. Pneumonia vs. Normal): 94.1%
- Tools: Deep Learning (CNNs), Tensorflow/Keras, Python, Jupyter, and Google Colab

SentArg

☐ GITHUB.COM/LUCKYOS-CODE/ARGU

- Argument retrieval model for Touché @ CLEF 2020 1st Shared Task on Argument Retrieval.
- The task was to retrieve arguments from the provided dataset of the focused crawl with content from online debate portals for the 50 given topics, covering a wide range of controversial issues.
- Tools: NLP, Sentiment Analysis, Doc2Vec/Word2Vec, Python, Docker, and Google Cloud

Publications

SentArg: A Hybrid Doc2Vec/DPH Model with Sentiment Analysis Refinement

CHRISTIAN STAUDTE AND LUCAS LANGE, IN: CLEF 2020 WORKING NOTES

% ceur-ws.org/Vol-2696/paper_191.pdf

Further Education _____

2021	Fundamentals of Neuroscience Part 1, HarvardX	edX
2020	Deep Learning Specialization, deeplearning.ai	Coursera
2020	Machine Learning, Stanford Online	Coursera
2020	Blockchain A-Z™: Learn How To Build Your First Blockchain, SuperDataScience	Udemy
2020	TRIZ User (Level 1), Target Invention	TRIZ-Trainer

Personal_

Languages	German Native, English B2/C1, and French B1/B2
Hobbies	Fitness, Reading, Hiking, Travel, and Cinema
Interests	Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Digital Ethics & Privacy, Environment, Data Science, and Medicine